我在找一个叫林肯·布伦斯的人
I'm looking for Lincoln Burrows
杀了副总统哥哥的凶手
Man killed the VP's brother
为什么你要这么急着找布伦斯?
Why you want to see him?
因为他是我哥哥
He's my brother
-我正在想办法救你出去  -这不可能
-I'll get you out.  -It's impossible
除非监狱是你设计的
Not if you designed the place
你见过设计蓝图了?
You've seen the blueprints
何止见过
Better than that
我把他们纹在了身上
I've got 'em on me
尼克·萨维恩
Nick Savrinn
从现在开始,你们两个死定了
As of now, both of you are dead
我是贝利克
This is Bellick
我们这区已经被突破了
Our wing has been breached
玛丽莲  不要!
Marilyn, no!
在监狱里
The chair isn't the only way
行刑不一定非得通过电椅
to take a man's life in prison
-你干什么?  -即使你父亲早就有麻烦了
-What are you doing?  -Your father's already in trouble
我们谁也帮不了他
There's nothing we can do about it
快点! 我第一次做P.I.
Come on!My first assignments on PI were up here
就是来这里清理有毒物质
cleaning out toxic mould
P.I.到不了那里
PI didn't go there
我们也从不派犯人去那里
We'd never assign inmates to do that
泰勒·罗伯特
Tyler, Robert
这一定是你女儿喽
And this here must be your daughter
这事算成了 我们不再需要他了
It's over. We don't need him
那你也不能杀了他
You're not gonna kill him
团队利益
One for the team
十七天后
(Michael) 17 days from now
我哥哥将坐上电椅
they strap my brother to an electric chair
电压高达5万伏的电流将通过他身体
Send 50,000 volts coursing through his body
只因为一个莫须有的罪名
for a crime he didn't commit
我是来这里救他的
I'm here to make sure that doesn't happen
我来狐狸河监狱 差不多3个星期了
I've been in Fox River nearly three weeks now
这期间  我已可以从我狱室后面出来
In that time,I've got out the back of my cell
进入到横贯监狱的旧蒸汽管道
and into the old steam pipes that run beneath the prison
这些管道就是出口
Those pipes are our way out
把这个地方
Think of this place
当作是美国地图
like it's a map of the US
我们的狱室在那 那是纽约市
Our cell over there, that's New York City
而医务室  我们的出口 那是加州
The infirmary, our exit, that's California
我们脚下连贯这两地的...
The pipes beneath us that connect the two...
是66大道
Route 66
66大道
我们自由之车的车票
Our ticket out of here
我猜是晚上行动吧
I assume we're doing this at night?
对
That's right
这里看守这么严实 嫩鸡 而你的老哥
We're locked up, fish,and your boy
被单独监禁
is in solitary
我们这些鸟儿 怎样才可以飞出笼子
How we just gonna fly out of our cages
到你的狱室去呢?
and  right into your cell
怎么去纽约市?
right into New York City?
不用到我狱室
You're not
我们到时会在半路会合的
You're gonna meet me halfway
在圣路易?
In St Louis
66大道在那楼下底部穿过
Route 66 runs beneath that building
在这些管道上面
It's the only building
只有这座楼
sitting on top of those tunnels
我们只要趁做P.I.的时候
All we gotta do is get in there, on PI
在那里弄一个出口
and dig ourselves an on-ramp
很快  我们就到医务室
Shortly after, we hit the infirmary
到时我们就会逃出监狱了
Then we'll be outside those walls
那边是什么地方?
What's in there?
是一个旧储物室
It's an old storage room
约翰可以利用他在这里的关系
John here can pull all the stringsThere's gotta be some actual work to be done in there for me
没那么容易  嫩鸡
(John) It's not that easy, fish
那是禁区
That's a restricted area
我得要有个借口 骗过狱警
I gotta be able to justify it to the bulls
让他们派我们去那里干活
There's gotta be some actual work to be done in there for me
以便可以进去
to get in there
你明白吗?
You follow?
那你尽快找到
Then you better figure it out
因为若我们进不了那房子
Cos if we don't get in that room
我们就出不去
we're not getting out of here.
好像有什么瞒着我?
I'm feeling kind of left out
纽约?  加州?
New York? California?
圣路易?
St Louis?
我们在谈什么呢?
What are we discussing?
棒球而已
We're talking baseball, actually
是吗?
Oh.
关于这个话题
Now, that's a subject
我恰巧有点了解
I know quite a bit about.
真可惜
What a shame
我们说完了
The conversation's over
真的吗?
Really, now
你们就这样
That any way
对待一个队友的吗?
to treat a team-mate?
不管你们愿意与否
I'm coming along on this endeavour
我是一定要和你们纠缠下去了
whether you like it or not
况且我还有
Cos I got
一副好嗓子
a hell of a singing voice otherwise
我不会带上这个贱人的
I won't take that piece of crap along
一定不会
I won't do it
我也不会
Me neither
我们不必带上他的
We won't have to
他很快就不会缠住我们了
He'll be out of the picture soon enough
州政府提供了2万5千美元保险金
The state provides $25,000 insurance
加上从伊利诺斯州惩教署职员基金会的捐款
plus donations from the Corrections Officers' Foundation...
监狱长  我现在不关心这个
That's the last thing on my mind right now, Warden
你找到凶手了吗?
Do you know who killed him?
我们掌握了些线索
We have some leads
但我可以向你保证
But I can promise you this
我们决不会让凶手逍遥法外的
We are not gonna rest until we find out what happened
他的照片不见了
His pictures are missing
这里有我们女儿的照片
He had a photo of our daughter in here
不用担心
Not to worry
我们会查清楚的
We'll find them
我求过他
I begged him
让他不要干这份工作
not to take this job
莎尔娜
Shauna
我很抱歉
I am so sorry
我陪你出去坐车
I'll walk you to your car
队长
Captain
我要和你谈一下
need to speak with you for a second
走廊见
I'll meet you in the hallway
我要抓到那个龟孙子凶手
I want the son of a bitch who did this
不管你用什么办法 你都要把他找出来
Now, you do whatever you need to do to find him
明白吗?
You understand?
这有5个箱子  过来帮一下忙好吗?
We got five boxes.Wanna give me a hand?
维罗妮卡?
Veronica
那电话是典型的恐吓手段
That phone call was  tactics scare
他们就想吓一下你
That's they want.
让我们望而生畏
They want to scare us from doing what they know we can do
-那该怎么做?  -把他们曝光
-And what's that?  -Expose them
多诺万小姐  这家伙又来烦你了吗?
Is this guy bothering you again?  Miss Donovan?
不 卢卡斯 那个晚上是我的过错
No, Lukasz, the other night was my fault
是个误会
It was a misunderstanding
如果你有什么需要
OK. But if you need anything...
相信我
Trust me
要有事我第一个找你
you'll be the first person I call
让我来
Here, let me
这些箱子
Those boxes
装着七年来
contain seven years
上诉案件的档案
of criminal appellant work
如果有先例
If there's a precedent in there somewhere
可以使得林肯的死刑缓期执行 我们一定可以找到的
that can help us suspend Lincoln's execution,we're gonna find it
你可以放到门边  卢卡斯
You can leave those by the door
我会搬进去的
I'll bring them in
好的
Oh, that's OK
我这里有你的钥匙
I've got your key right here
如果我不知情 还以为卢卡斯痴情于你呢
If I didn't know better,I'd say Lukasz was sweet on you.
有趣
Very funny
火
Fire
什么?
What?
用火  我们把那地方烧为平地
Fire. We burn the place down
对我们有什么用?
How's that gonna help us?
几年前  礼拜堂发生大火
A few years ago, the chapel burnt down
惩教署意识到
and the DOC realised
有一些有毒物质
they had some toxic issues
像石棉  导火线
You know, asbestos, lead paint, you name it
他们找不到承包商来清理
They couldn't find a contractor
所以他们派狱犯来做
so they put the inmates on the job
每次我们都在那呆5-6小时
We spent, like, five, six hours in there at a time
但有一点比较好的是
But the good news is
基本上没有守卫来巡逻
no guards came around almost at all
你有办法带我们到那吗?
Can you get us in there?
我仔细考虑过了
I've been doing a little, uh... thinking
我要一张P.I.的工作证
I'm gonna need a PI card, aren't I?
我是说
I mean
那边是起事的地方
that's where this whole thing is happening
对吗?
isn't it?
很快就给你
It's on its way
你在敷衍我  对吗?
You're slow-walking me, aren't you?
我为什么要这么做?
Why would I do that?
你觉得贝利克会因狱警鲍勃那件事
You think Bellick's gonna pop me
把我抓起来
for shanking that CO, Bob
也许
Maybe
你们会悄悄跑去告诉他  对吗?
you'll take a little walk, tell him for yourself?
这样你们就可以摆脱我了
And I'll be out of here for good
我有你的一些秘密
Well, I got news for you
如果我因杀了鲍勃被抓起来
If I go down for killing Bob
我不会就此作罢的
believe me,I'm gonna take a little walk of my own
我会向他们禀明 你在你便池后面挖的洞
Tell 'em about that hole you got behind your toilet
这么说来...
So...
P.I.的工作证怎样?
How about that PI card?
你还记得吗
I don't know if you remember
在5年级的那个夏天
but that summer before fifth grade
我和你住了两星期时
when I stayed with you a couple weeks
你认为我打烂了玻璃咖啡桌
and you thought I broke your glass coffee table?
你回家时  我否认了
And when you came home, I denied it
但你告诉我
But you told me
对咖啡桌你可以不在乎
you could care less about the coffee table
但你不想我因此撒谎
you just didn't want me lying to you
你说我说出事实
And you said I'd feel a lot better
会觉得舒服点的
if I just told you the truth
而你保证不会生气
And you promised not to be angry
我记得
I remember
对  是我打烂的
Well, I broke it
我知道
I know
如果你心里
You know, if there's anything
有什么要说
that you want to get off your chest
你可以告诉我
you can tell me
我也保证不会生气
And I promise I won't get angry
你想知道是不是我杀了那人
You want to know if I killed that guy
当时我去那里  是想干点坏事
I, uh, went there planning to do something wrong
但我没杀那个人
But I didn't kill that guy
有人蓄意制造了我杀人的假象
Someone's working hard to make it look like I did
不管怎样  仍有机会不用执行死刑
Anyway, there's a chance the execution may not happen
什么?
What?
维罗妮卡正在帮我
Veronica's working on my case
今天有个记者来找我
and I got a reporter coming today
她相信我是无辜的
who believes I'm innocent
因此我还不用死
So I ain't dead yet
LJ  看着我
LJ. Look at me
你要有信念  孩子
You gotta have faith, kid
坚持你的信念
Just have a little faith
凯勒曼
Kellerman
怎样了?
Well?
搞定了
Taken care of
很好
Good
现在进行第二步计划
Now move on to the second thing
如果你见到我们在看的东西
If you could see what we're looking at...
相信我  布伦斯会收到信息的
believe me,Burrows is gonna get the message
这个你向我保证过了
Which is what you've assured me of before
而这信息
Yet that message
总是退回到发送者
keeps getting returned to sender
现在着手第二步计划 然后向我报告
Now move on the second thing and report back
我们现在去
We're headed there now
你想得太多了
You're thinking too much
是啊  但没办法
Yeah. God forbid
在找到那个杀手之前
He'll toss every cell in this block
他会将整个监狱挖地三尺
until he finds the killer
他找到这里时
He tosses this one
他会轻易找到后面那个洞的
he'll find the hole back there in a heartbeat
我知道
I know
我们得举报他
We got to turn T-Bag in
只有这样做才会停止搜查
That's the only way it'll stop
我们若举报他 他会泄漏我们的秘密
We turn him in, he'll talk
看来无论怎样都是死路一条  对吗?
So we're screwed either way, aren't we?
哪个房间?
Which one?
就在那
Right there
圣路易
St Louis
你们来这干什么?!
What the hell are you doing here?
清理工作队 我们以为这是储物室
Cleanup detail. We thought this was storage
这像是个储物室吗
This look like storage to you?
白痴 这是禁区
idiot  It's a restricted area
这是狱警休息室
a CO break room
退出去!
Now back it up
给我退出去!
Back it up, now!
对不起
Sorry, Officer
这种情况不会再发生了
It won't happen again
他妈的休息室
A freakin' break room?
你在开玩笑吧?
Are you kidding me?
房子翻新后他们一定换了房间
They must have changed it since the retrofit
狱警就守在那里
The bulls are camped out in there.
他们不会离开的
They'll never leave.
你有后备计划吗?
Got a backup plan?
没有
There isn't one
在管道上面
It's the only room
只有这个房间
on top of that pipe
这是出去的唯一方法
It's the only way out,
我们还得折回那里
We gotta get back in there
没可能  嫩鸡
Impossible, fish
未必  过来看看
Maybe not. Check it out
我不懂你说什么
I don't get it
他怎么可以进去?
How come they let him in?
他是囚犯理事
He's a trustee
拥有很高的安全权限
Ones with high security clearance
为什么是他?
Why him?
他们信得过他
He can be trusted.
怎么才可以成为囚犯理事?
How does one become a trustee?
只要三十年来没有不良记录
Have a spotless record for the last 30 years
没不良记录
for the last 30 years
我们的刑期加起来都没这么多
Pretty much counts us out
看来得让他加入我们
Which means we've gotta get him on board
算了吧 他不领任何人的情的
Forget it. The guy's a boy scout
韦斯特莫兰德 先生?
Mr Westmoreland
你好 迈克尔
Hey, Michael
找到你的猫了吗?
You found your cat yet?
还没
Still MIA
你可以另找一只
You could always get another
我并不想要其他的
I don't want another
而且那样毫无意义
Besides, it's a moot point
她已经在我心中根深蒂固
She was grandfathered
她不在了 也不要别的宠物
Once she's gone, no more pets
如果你出狱了  这就不是个问题了
Wouldn't be an issue if you were on the outside
还在打那个主意啊?
Still tugging on that leash, eh?
是的
Yup
而这一次
And this is the part
我正式向你发出邀请
where I extend a formal invitation
你仍觉得我是大盗库珀么?
Cos you still think I'm DB Cooper?
我不是觉得  是知道
I don't think. I know
据我所知
The way I see it
由于你开车撞死人
you're in here doing 60 to life
被判60年至终身监禁
for vehicular manslaughter
原该判你20年
It would have been 20
但你的车是偷来的
but the car you were in was stolen
变成犯另一重罪的谋杀
Felony murder rule cubes every sentence
所以你还在这里
And here you are
撞死那个女人是个意外
Hitting that woman was an accident
但那车?
But the car?
没人会无缘无故偷车的
No one accidentally steals a car
问题就出现在这
So the question is
为什么查尔斯 韦斯特莫兰德会
why would Charles Westmoreland be in Arizona boosting a car
在他住处十个州外
ten states away from where he lived
离墨西哥边境10英里远的亚利桑拿州开车狂飚呢?
and only ten miles from the Mexican border
还有  为什么事情发生的两天前
And why, two days before that
有人从波特兰一汽车旅馆
would someone make a phone call
打电话给他妻子
to his wife from a motel in Portland
而这旅馆恰巧在飞机场附近呢?
a stone's throw away from the airport out of which
而电话后不久
shortly after
305航班被一个叫库珀的人劫持
flight 305 was hijacked by one DB Cooper
飞机被劫后七小时
Seven hours after the hijacking
记录表明查尔斯 韦斯特莫兰德
records show Charles Westmoreland
因膝盖受伤在杨百翰市一家小诊所受过治疗
was treated for a busted knee at a free clinic in Brigham City
七小时内  要从波特兰  俄勒冈
Only way to get from Portland, Oregon to Brigham City
到犹他州的杨百翰市
Utah in seven hours
除了开一辆打破世界记录的汽车
is in a car breaking every land speed record
还有就是坐飞机
known to man,or flying
大家都知道库珀
It's public record DB Cooper
在起飞后一小时从那架727飞机跳出
jumped out of that 727 about an hour after take off
在10000英尺的高空
Taking a dive at 10,000 feet
拿着150万美金  跳了伞
with 1.5 million in cash
而降落伞是仓促中装备的
and a hastily packed parachute
可能降落得很不理想
might make for a pretty rough landing
不理想到摔坏了骨头
Rough enough to shatter some bones
可能就是左膝
Maybe even a left knee
落地时  库珀将安排车来接他
DB Cooper would have had a car waiting for him
根据1971年DMV记录
According to DMV records, in 1971
查尔斯·韦斯特莫兰德很荣幸的 是一辆65年产雪佛莱的主人
Charles Westmoreland was the proud owner of a 65 Chevy Nova
而在阿利桑那州边界 发现一辆65年产的雪佛莱
As it happens, a 65 Chevy Nova
车牌已被刮花
with the registration number scraped off
被抛弃在一旁
was found abandoned with a blown gasket
气缸爆了
along the Arizona border
就在你用偷来的车 撞到那女人的地方
a mile or two away from where you accidentally hit that woman
一两里开外
with your stolen car
这故事有意思
Interesting story
这人更有意思
Interesting man
但有一点你解释不了
But you didn't answer one thing
是什么?
What's that?
可能我确实伤到了膝盖
Maybe I did hurt my knee
我确实偷了车
I did steal that car
我也确实意外的撞了那可怜的女人
and I did accidentally hit that poor lady
但是我11月24日
But how could I have hijacked a plane in Portland on November 24th
我因为醉酒闹事被判监禁30天
when I was in Folsom
又怎么能去波特兰劫持飞机呢?
finishing up a 30-day drunk and disorderly?
我希望你不要把所有的越狱希望 都寄托在那笔钱上
I hope you weren't hanging this whole escape on that money
因为我不是拥有者
cos I'm not the one in possession of it
不过还是谢谢你的邀请
Thanks for the invite, though
维罗妮卡
Veronica
维罗妮卡  别这样
Veronica, come on
我们没事了
We're OK
这怎么算没事呢  尼克?
How is this OK, Nick?
有人要杀我们
Somebody just tried to kill us
-我知道  我在现场  -那就不要当作没事  好吗?
-I know. I was there.  -Then act like it,OK?
我们眼睁睁的看着一个人 在我们面前被烧死
We just watched a man burn to death right in front of us
我的天
My God
卢卡斯   我的天啊
Lukasz... My God
没事了  没事了  没事了
It's OK. It's OK
我们居然抛下他不管
We just left him there
我们为他做什么都于事无补 他一开门就没了命
There was nothing we could do.He was dead as soon as he opened the door
我很想弄清楚这一切怎么回事 尼克
I am trying so hard to understand all this,Nick.
这些人到底是谁  他们想干什么
Who these people are, what they want
我们怎么可以不报警就离开那里了呢?
How we walked away without calling the police
我们这么做是因为我们惹的 这些人不杀了我们是不会罢手的
We did it because these people we're dealing with won't stop until we're dead
现在  如果他们认为我们死了 就像现在我们看上去好像是死了一样
If they think we're dead  like they do right now,
可能我们就有点喘息的空间 我们来想想下一步怎么做
maybe we get a little breathing room here, we figure out what our next move is.
不  我们应该去报警
We should go to the police
我一直以来也是像你那样想的
I've been thinking the same thing
但是  你知道吗 警察是斗不过他们的
But you know what?They're bigger than the police
如果我们去报警 我们这么做
We go to the authorities and all we're gonna be doing
就是告诉他们我们还活着
it's broadcast to them that we're still alive
这样  我们又成为他们暗杀的目标了
and then we got that target right on our backs again
我们不能永远躲下去
We can't hide forever
不  不  可能不必永远躲
No, no. Maybe not forever
不过我知道有个地方
But...I think I know a place we can
可以让我们躲一阵子
at least for a little while
我们只须自己混进去了
We just have to go in there ourselves then
我说了  除非那老人加入 否则是不可能的
Like I said,unless the old man's in it's not possible
而且即使可以进去 那里有守卫
And even if it were, the guards in there
不会看不见我们在他们眼皮底下纵火
won't just sit back and watch us start a fire
这点我已经想到解决办法
See, I already figured that part out
我一直在想的
I been thinking
怎么解决?
And?
还记得你在主教的办公室做的那事吗?
That thing you're doing in the Pope's office
使用橡胶粘合剂?
You using rubber cement?
然后?
Yeah
-你能弄点出来吗?  -也许可以  为什么这么问?
-Can you get some out?  -Maybe. Why?
守卫室有个咖啡壶  对吗?
Look, there's a coffee maker in the guards' room, right?
我认识一位朋友
I got a hook-up
在厨房里面干活
with one of my boys in the kitchen
如果我们能涂点橡胶粘合剂在咖啡壶底部
If we can get rubber cement in the bottom of that coffee pot
加热装置一打开...
when the burner goes on...
这主意不错
It's a good idea
但没有韦斯特莫兰德
But without Westmoreland
我们进不去那房子的
we're never getting in that room
他不想成为出逃的一份子?
He doesn't want any part of this?
不想
No
那他想要什么?
Then what does he want?
他必有所求
He's gotta want something
每个人都有其所求
Everybody wants something
过来
come on
真乖
That's a good girl.
真想不到
I don't believe it
谢谢
Thank you
不客气
You're welcome
你在哪里找到她的?
Where'd you find her?
在礼拜堂旁边的院子里
In the yard, by the chapel
为什么我感觉像有什么企图
Why do I get the feeling there's a string attached to this?
没什么企图  举手之劳
Not a string. Just a favour
我不是 库珀
I'm not DB Cooper
没关系
That's all right
因为我想要做的
Cos it's not gonna take DB Cooper
不必拜托到  库珀
to do what I need done
什么事?
What's that?
我只要你在指定时间
All I want you to do
拿指定的咖啡壶进守卫室
is take a certain coffee pot into the guard room at a certain time
然后打开加热装置
and turn the burner on
为什么要这么做?
Why?
如果那里失火的话
Let's just say it'd be in everyone's best interests
我想这对大家都最好不过了
if a fire were to start in there
猫儿  你觉得他像火神吗?
Marilyn, did you think he was the arsonist type?
我不是
I'm not
我是清道夫
I'm the cleanup crew type
能从各种渠道搞到工具的人
The type that gets access to all kinds of tools
迈克尔  非常感谢你找回小猫
Michael, I'm grateful for this
真的
I really am
自从我进来这地方
but I've made it a point to keep my nose clean
我就打定主意不惹事生非
ever since I walked into this place
32年来没有过不良记录
32 years without a blemish
我希望有条件成为 假释榜上面的人
If that parole board date ever comes,I want to be ready
我不能坏了这个大事
I can'tjeopardise that
对不起
Sorry
迈克尔
Michael
还是很谢谢你  真的
Thanks, though. Really
经历了那场骚乱
After what you went through in the riot
我还以为你会请一天假
I thought you'd take a day off
我没事
I'm fine
同时也
I, uh...
找不到人来代替我
I couldn't find anybody to cover for me, anyway
希望你不会觉得你欠我什么
I hope you don't feel like you owe me anything
当然没有
I do
我...
I'm, uh...
真的很感激你为我做的事
I really appreciate what you did for me
不过呢?
But?
但是你告诉我
But you told me that
你跟P.I.去过水管槽隙
you had been up in the crawlspace for PI
而P.I.是不会被派到那里的
and PI was never assigned to go there
针打完了  对吗?
We're done here, right?
迈克尔  不要这样
Michael, don't be like that
我只是想知道一些答案
I just... I just want some answers
谢谢你打的针  医生
Thanks for the shot, Doc
我叫苏·帕尔森 要闻报的
Sue Parsons, Headline Press
谢谢你的到来
Thanks for coming by
感谢你给我时间
I appreciate you taking the time
很感激你关注我的案子
I appreciate you looking at my case
你有什么要说的?
So what can you tell me?
据我所知  有很多人
From what I understand,you have numerous people
在为你奔走
working on your behalf as we speak
对
Yeah. Um, well...
维罗妮卡·多诺万  她是我的代表律师
Veronica Donovan, she's my attorney
尼克·萨维恩
and Nick Savrinn
他在正义计划工作
He works at Project Justice
萨维恩  好的
Savrinn. OK
他们有什么进展吗?
Have they gotten very far?
还没有什么可以提交到法庭的 还没有
Nothing to go to court with. Not yet, anyway
你想过是时候放手了吗?
You ever think it's just time to let go?
接受发生过的事实?
Accept what happened?
放手?  是的
Let go, yeah
接受发生过的事实?  从来没有
Accept what happened? Never
你会接受吗?
I mean, would you?
如果有人陷害了你 毁了你的人生呢?
If someone had set you up, destroyed your life?
我在想你给朋友和亲人
I guess I'm thinking in terms of the anguish
带来的痛苦和煎熬
it's caused your friends and loved ones
关心我的人  他们都相信我
People who care about me believe me
我所在意的就只有这些
That's all that matters to me right now
这是我的全部
It's all I've got
你有个孩子叫小林肯 简称LJ?
You have a son. Lincoln Jr. LJ
对  为什么这么问?
Yeah. Why?
有线人告诉我 如果你承认有罪
I have a source that tells me if you accept what happened
停止继续上诉
and stop fighting your execution
你的儿子就会安然无恙
your son will be left out of this
否则
If not
我想今早你和你儿子的再见 便是永远的再见
I hope you said goodbye to him when he left here this morning
你究竟是谁?
Who are you?
总得有个姓布伦斯的死
One Burrows is gonna die
哪一个死取决于你
Up to you which one
你是谁?  你究竟是谁?!
Who are you? Who are you?
不能让她走!
Don't let her go!
她恐吓我的儿子!  不要!
She threatened my son
Please, no! Not my son!
你是LJ 布伦斯?
LJ Burrows?
对
Yeah?
我是青少年法庭的官员哈尔
I'm Officer Hale, Juvenile Court
我们要对住处做个小调查
We need to do a survey of the residence
确保这里的环境
make sure your environment
对你的缓刑有好处
reflects the terms of your probation
你父母在吗?
Your parents home?
不  不过他们随时会回来
No, but they'll be home any minute
好吧  开始
Well then. I'll get started
LJ和他爸爸...
LJ and his dad
你还没说今早事情怎样了?
You never said how it went
应该还好
Sounded fine
当然  每个十五岁的孩子都只对他母亲说
Everything a 15-year-old boy
还好
tells his mother is fine
我没冒犯的意思
No offence
我可以看看你的证件吗?
but can I see some kind of identification?
当然可以
Sure
LJ  我们回来了
LJ, we're home
LJ  你在吗?
LJ, you here?
我的天
Oh, my God
放下电话  女士
Drop the phone, lady
我的警告只有一次
This is the only warning I'm giving you
放下电话
Drop it
快跑!
Run!
快点接  快点接
Pick up. Pick up, please
拜托应答  快点
Please answer, come on
LJ...
LJ?
我们不是来伤害你的
We're not here to hurt you
911...发送
911, send
你说你按4个键快
You really think you're gonna get to four buttons
还是我按一个快呢?
before I get to one?
来
Come on
LJ  快跑
LJ, get out of here!
妈妈?  妈妈?
Mom?
你要到哪里去  LJ?
Where you going?
你想从我这里得到什么?
What do you want?
合作  仅此而已
Cooperation. That's all
你想要合作?
You want cooperation?
我记得你的样子  你这狗娘养的!
I know what you look like, you son of a bitch
我要去报警
I'm going to the police
报警?
The police
我想这不是个好主意  LJ
I don't think that's such a good idea, LJ
我是说  手枪上有了你的指纹
with your prints on the murder weapon and all
我没碰过凶器
I didn't touch the murder weapon
当然你没有
Of course not
这个你知我知
I know that, and you know that
令弹道专家相信你的话
I don't think you'll have much luck
恐怕没那么容易
convincing Ballistics of that
你们这些人到底是谁?
Who the hell are you people?
只是关心你的邻居
Just concerned neighbours
听到瑞克斯家有点吵  便过来看看
Heard a bit of a ruckus at the Rixs' house
心想  糟了
Gosh
我们就像真的看到事情的经过
I guess we really should have seen it coming
想想你的不良表现
All the signs were there
吸毒  学校表现差
drug use, decline in academic performance
真没想到
But we didn't think
他会这么做
he'd do this
没人会信的
No one's gonna believe that
他们会信的
Yes, they will
他们抓到你时 他们会抓到你的...LJ
And when they catch you, and they will
他们会把你 当作成年人来拷问的
they'll try you as an adult
你知道那意味着什么吗?
You know what that means?
我们可以帮你  LJ
We can help you, LJ
我们是你的唯一希望
We're the only hope you got
不  不是的
No, you're not
是她自找的
She made that choice, not you
我们去找那孩子
Let's find the kid
你找回你的玛丽莲了?
You got Marilyn back
当然
Sure did
很好
That's good
你戒烟多久了?
How long ago you quit smoking?
9年多一点
Uh, a little over nine years now
你不介意的  对吗?
You don't mind, do you?
我和你一向很好  查尔斯
I feel a kinship with you, Charles
比跟其他囚犯好
More than any other con here
我们也一起经历了许多  对吗?
And we've seen a lot. Haven't we?
对
Sure have
如果我说错了  你纠正我
Then correct me if I'm wrong
我一向待你不薄
I've always treated you fair
我一直很感激这点
I've always appreciated that fact
自鲍勃他18岁起  我就认识他了
I'd known Bob since he was 18 years old
这工作是我找给他的
I got him this job
你可以想像我有多么愧疚
You can imagine how responsible I feel
我帮不了你  长官
I can't help you with that, boss
我觉得你可以
I think you can
听说他是在你狱室前死的
Word is he died in front of your cell
事情发生时  你在场
And you were right here when it happened
我们在这打滚这么多年
We've both been around long
都知道  一个囚犯若告密
enough to know that when a con starts that snitching business
他是自寻死路
he's not long for this world
不要让我难做  长官
Don't put me in that position, boss
我离开狱室前  你若不告诉我谁杀了鲍勃
If you don't tell me who killed Bob before I leave this cell
我们的交情就到此为止
our friendship goes with it
这猫不错
That's a nice cat
韦斯特莫兰德知道
Westmoreland knows
而他嘴巴不太严
And his jaw ain't that strong
这是什么呢?
What's this?
没什么
Nothing
你暗恋人家
You stalker
我没有
I am not a stalker
我只是...
I just...
想不明白
I don't get it
不明白什么?
What is there to get?
他上面的资料不符  对吗?
He doesn't fit the profile.Right?
这人大学毕业
The man's got a graduate degree
他住在我家附近
He lives in my neighbourhood
像他那样的人 会在特维尔大街出现
Guys that like hang out in Streeterville
喝纯正威士忌
They drink single malt scotch.
花200美元买棒球队季票
they pay $200 for Cubs tickets
他们没必要抢银行的
They don't rob banks
也许他买不起季度票
Maybe he couldn't afford season tickets
也许那就是他抢银行的原因
Maybe that's why he robbed the bank
谢谢  不过我是说真的
Thank you. I'm actually being serious
我可以问你些东西吗?
Can I ask you something?
可以
Yeah
为什么你这么关心这个?
Why do you care so much?
因为他对我说谎了
Cos he lied to me
男人都在说谎
They all lie to you
也许这儿真正谈上心的只有他
Maybe because he's the one guy in here I can actually get to
只有他
The one guy
我能不同对待
I can make a difference with
回家吧  孩子
Go home, girl
你再这么自寻烦恼
You keep burning it at both ends like this
会把自己折磨到疯的
you're gonna drive yourself crazy
晚安
Good night
很遗憾  布伦斯
I'm sorry, Burrows
救护人员赶到时
Both of them were dead
他们两人都死了
by the time the paramedics got there
我的儿子呢?
What about my son?
他失踪了
He's missing
警察正视他为逃犯
Police are treating him as a fugitive
逃犯?
Fugitive?
凶器上有他指纹
They found his prints on the murder weapon
不可能
That's impossible
我...我要打电话给他
I... I, uh...  I need to call him
不  我做不到
No, I can't do that
你什么意思? 你做不到?
What do you mean?You can't do that?
-他就要没命了  -布伦斯
-His life's in danger!Look, -Burrows.
警察和我说明了
The police instructed me that
案件正在调查中
this is an ongoing investigation
你和你儿子这样的联系
And as such, any contact you make with your son
可能会帮助和教唆他潜逃
could potentially aid and abet him as a fugitive
对不起
I'm sorry
狱长  拜托了
Warden, please!
走吧
Let's go
真可怜
That's messed up, man
他知道了吗?
Jeez. Does he even know?
我想还没
I don't think so
他在这儿
Go ahead, toss 'em
有事么?T
What's up, T?
我们是好兄弟  对吗?
We're family, right?
对
Hell, yeah. We are
我现在有麻烦  我需要你帮忙
Well, I'm in a quandary and I need your help
说说
Name it
贝利克在这里的搜索越来越紧了
Bellick's squeezing tighter and tighter round here
你说得对
You're right .Eventually
总会有人告密的
somebody's mouth is gonna start moving
而现在
Thing is
洛奇  如果我因这个被抓
Trokey, if I get popped for this
加上我的前科
what with my priors
还有我的暴力倾向行为背景
and predisposition to violent behaviour...
我一辈子都要呆在这儿了
I'll spend the rest of my life in the SHU
但如果你自首认了
But if you come forward
以你只有毒品的前科
with only a drug conviction
再加上你是主动自首...
and a whole lotta remorse...
我做不到  帝博格
I can't do that
-我还没说完  -不用说了
-I ain't finished.  -No need.
我又没杀人  凭什么替你顶罪
I ain't going down for murdering no hack
你能理解的  对吗?
I mean, you understand that, don't you?
你不会生我气吧?
You ain't mad, are you?
是的  洛奇 我不会生你气的
No, Trokey. I'm not mad
我要出去  我要去找他
I need out. I gotta find him
我们会出去的
You will
一起出去  很快
Both of us. Soon
他们在害我的家人  迈克尔
They're coming after my family,Michael.
你要相信我
You gotta trust me
很快就可以出去
We're gonna...
很快可以出去?
"We're gonna get this done
怎么出去?
How?
告诉我  迈克尔  告诉我
Tell me, Michael. Tell me
你出不去的  对吗?
You can't, can you?
我现在就要出去
I gotta get outta here now
LJ有危险
LJ's in trouble
斯科菲尔德
Scofield
怎么了?
How about it?
相信我
Just stick with me
布鲁斯  你好!
Yo, Bruce. Hey
如果你从那出去
If you go out there
他们会枪杀你的
they will gun you down
我管不了那么多了
I don't care any more
你最好想想你在做些什么
You better start thinking what are you doing?
因为你若死了  就帮不到LJ了
Cos you can't help LJ if you're dead
那边发生什么事了?
What the hell's going on in here?
有麻烦是吗?
Huh? We got a problem?
不是
No
那站起来
Well, then get on your feet
走!
Let's go!
我操...
Son of a...
那边究竟发生什么事了?
What the hell's going on at building two?
进来
Come in
警卫休息室失火
Fire in the CO break room
谢谢
Thanks
我这么做不是为了你
I didn't do it for you
找到火源
We found the source
有人抽这个吗?
Someone in here smoke these?
"幸运牌" ?
Bilsons?
贝利克
Bellick
贝利克上尉   有人要见你
Captain Bellick?I've got someone to see you
你他妈的想干嘛?
What the hell do you want?
我知道谁杀了鲍勃  长官
I know who killed Bob, sir
噢...
Uh-oh
我不知怎么会在那的
I don't know how that got there
不是我的 我们走
It's a mock
不是我的
It's a mock!
你陷害我!
You set me up
你杀狱警已经够坏了
Bad enough that you killed a guard
不要想着
Don't try to lay it off
让别人背这个黑锅
on somebody else
你陷害我
You set me up!
他陷害我的
He set me up...
你父亲在这里住的?
Wow.Your father lived here?
对  他想住在
Yeah  He wanted some place
地图上找不到的地方
that was completely off the grid
一个连政府都不知道的地方
a place the government didn't know existed
偷接过来的电线
Tapped into the power lines
用井供水
A well supplies the place with water
他人生的最后几年 都没有离开过这里
Last few years of his life he barely left the property
真的很...
It's...
对
Yeah
这么多年来  劳精费神的 对付警察和检察官还有法官
You spend so many years fighting cops, prosecutors, judges
这些人因一些你没有做过的事
trying to take your freedom
要夺走你的自由
for something you didn't do,
而你倾尽所有来打官司
you use every cent you had in attorney's fees
最后一个子儿都没有剩
you wind up losing anyway...
他人生中的15年
15 years of his life
他儿子大部分的童年时光
Almost all of his son's childhood
我想我能原谅他要躲起来
I guess I can forgive him for wanting to hide away
一个人孤独生活
Be left alone
我们住在这里将会很安全
We'll be safe here
直到我们想出下一步怎么做
until we figure out our next move
等一等  等等
Hey, hold up here a minute. Hold up, here
我有点搞不懂了
Seems to be a bit of confusion
我应该弄清楚
I'm supposed to be on this detail
我不这么认为
I don't think so
约翰
Oh, John
你没开玩笑吧?
You can't be serious
我们一起开创
Not after our long, illustrious history
这么辉煌的历史
we shared together
那些在纽约市晚上
All those nights in New York City
在加州
In California
在圣...
In St
路易
Louis
这些时光
They were good times
真是美好  对吗  约翰?
weren't they, John?
我们来告诉狱警这些有多美妙
Tell the badge here about 'em
如果你不想去的话
Cos if you don't want to...
我可以去
I certainly could
给我搞得好好的
I want this place gutted
墙要清理干净
The dry wall's gotta be torn out
杂物要清掉
Studs gotta be removed
这里有有毒物质
Boss, we've got some toxic issues here
比如石棉
Asbestos to start with
那你向工会投诉去吧
Take it up with the union
我要说的是  这房间是你们要优先执行的任务
All I'm saying is this room's your only priority now
最好给我搞得像新的一样
It better be brand spanking new when you're done
如果有人敢耍小聪明
If anybody's thinking about getting cute
要偷运这些工具出去
trying to trunk one of these tools out of here
贝迪已经记录好
Brady's got the outline
每一件工具的清单
of every piece of hardware in here
而每天工作结束后
And at the end of every day
一件工具都不能少
every single piece better match up
否则你们就死定了
or you're all going to the hole
开工
Let's go
这里下面4英尺
This goes down four feet
连接到主管道
Connects to the main line below
我们要做的是把这口子敲大点
All we've gotta do is widen it
那么我们就有入口了
and we've got ourselves
到66大道的入口
an on-ramp to Route 66.
他们会听到的
Whoa, whoa, whoa.They're gonna hear this, man
不会的
They won't
别这样  宝贝  我们是一伙的了
Come on, pretty. We're a team now
要硬攻了
Best get crackin', eh?
闭嘴 杂毛
You. Shut up
你说你按四下快
You really think you're gonna get to four buttons
还是我按一下快?
before I get to one?
我没戴眼镜
I don't have my glasses
不如你读这个给我听听?
How about you read this for me?
告诉我最新的进展
Tell me the news,the latest developments
很明显  昨天在芝加哥金海岸公寓
Evidently there was an explosion
发生了一起爆炸事故
in a Gold Coast apartment in Chicago yesterday
煤气管
Gas line
里面的人全死了
Everyone inside was killed
可惜  还有吗?
Shame Anything else?
橡树公园那个男孩怎样了?
How about that kid up in Oak Park
那个据说杀了双亲的男孩?
the one who killed his parents?
他被抓了 真的吗?
Oh, they got him  They did?
现在被拘留起来了
He's in custody
好
Good
我想如果不抓他起来 还有更多人受牵连
I imagine heads would have rolled if he hadn't been caught
更多人受害
Lives would have been lost
能把报纸还给我么?
How about you hand that back to me?
既然这是昨天的新闻
Now that it's yesterday's news
我们可以放下了  对吗?
we can put it behind us, can't we?
翻开我们一生中崭新的一章
Move on to the next chapter of our lives
你们这么做  不仅仅是为我
You're not just doing this for me
也不是为了我哥哥
you know.Or my brother
他们在外面等你 副总统女士
They're ready for you, Madam Vice President
你们是为国效劳
You're doing it for your country
副总统女士  副总统女士!
Madam Vice President...
这边  副总统女士!
Madam Vice President, a question...